ALIEN was the beginning… Hell Has Just Been Relocated!
Galaxy of Terror is a action, adventure, horror film directed by Bruce D. Clark.
As a lone spaceship proceeds on its long voyage across space, the
crew are surprised to encounter a strange pyramid form.
Surprise turns to horror as one by one, they discover that their
darkest nightmares are all starting to become real.
The pyramid has to be behind it all somehow, but how can
they save themselves from its influence?
Cabren, played by Edward Albert.
Alumna, played by Erin Moran.
Kore, played by Ray Walston.
Commander Ilvar, played by Bernard Behrens.
Baelon, played by Zalman King.
Ranger, played by Robert Englund.
Galaxy of Terror (originally released as Mindwarp: An Infinity of Terror) is a
1981 American science fiction horror film directed by Bruce D.
Clark and produced by Roger Corman through New World Pictures.
It stars Edward Albert, Erin Moran, Ray Walston, Taaffe O'Connell, and
future horror film stars Sid Haig and Robert Englund.
Set in a dystopian future where humanity is a spacefaring race ruled by a sole person called "The Master," the
film features a space crew confronting primal fears after they are marooned on a distant planet.
The film has many of the hallmarks associated with the "B-movie" style Roger Corman became known for: low budget, up-and-coming production
personnel, and exploitive material, including a notorious scene in which a giant maggot rapes Dameia (Taaffe O'Connell).
It is also notable for its production design and visual effects, which were
created by James Cameron in one of his earliest filmmaking credits.
Released on September 4, 1981, the film has developed a cult following.
Critics have noted its influence on later productions,
most notably Cameron's own Aliens (1986).
The film explores themes of spacecraft, monster, gore, alien, murder.
The tone is dark and thought_provoking.